{
    "questions_and_answers": 
    [
       {
         "question": "When was Nitte Mahalinga Adyantaya Memorial Institute of Technology (NMAMIT) established?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT was established in 1986.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Is NMAMIT recognized by any regulatory body?",
         "answer": "Yes, NMAMIT is recognized by the All India Council for Technical Education (AICTE), New Delhi.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What is NMAMIT's rank in the National Institutional Ranking Framework (NIRF) 2023?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT is ranked in the rank band of 101-150 in NIRF 2023 by the Ministry of Education, Government of India.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Under which category has NMAMIT been placed for having high industry linkages?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT has been placed under the 'Platinum' category for high industry linkages by the AICTE-CII Survey of Industry-Linked Technical Institutes 2020.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Which university is NMAMIT affiliated with?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT is a constituent college of Nitte (Deemed to be University), Mangaluru.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What are the fifteen UG engineering programs offered by NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "The UG engineering programs offered are: Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence & Data Science, Biotechnology, Civil Engineering, Computer & Communication Engineering, Computer Science & Engineering, Computer Science (Cyber Security), Computer Science (Full Stack Development), Electrical & Electronics Engineering, Electronics & Communication Engineering, Electronics (VLSI Design & Technology), Electronics & Communication Engineering (ACT), Information Science & Engineering, Mechanical Engineering, and Robotics & Artificial Intelligence.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What are the UG engineering programs offered by NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "The UG engineering programs offered are: Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence & Data Science, Biotechnology, Civil Engineering, Computer & Communication Engineering, Computer Science & Engineering, Computer Science (Cyber Security), Computer Science (Full Stack Development), Electrical & Electronics Engineering, Electronics & Communication Engineering, Electronics (VLSI Design & Technology), Electronics & Communication Engineering (ACT), Information Science & Engineering, Mechanical Engineering, and Robotics & Artificial Intelligence.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "How many UG programs at NMAMIT are accredited by NBA under Tier - I category?",
         "answer": "Seven UG programs at NMAMIT are accredited by NBA under Tier - I category.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What are the PG programs offered by NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT offers PG programs in M.Tech. in seven disciplines and MCA program.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What are the seven disciplines for M.Tech. program at NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "The seven disciplines for M.Tech. program are Construction Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Cyber Security, Electric Vehicle Technology, Machine Design, Structural Engineering, and VLSI Design & Embedded Systems.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
        {
         "question": "What are the branches available for the M.Tech. program at NMAM Institute of Technology (NMAMIT)?",
         "answer": "The seven disciplines for M.Tech. program are Construction Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Cyber Security, Electric Vehicle Technology, Machine Design, Structural Engineering, and VLSI Design & Embedded Systems.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Does NMAMIT have provisions for research work leading to Ph.D.?",
         "answer": "Yes, all the departments at NMAMIT have qualified research guides for students interested in taking up research work leading to Ph.D.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What is the total area of NMAMIT's campus?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT's campus is spread over 125 acres.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What is the nearest airport to NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "The nearest airport to NMAMIT is Mangaluru International Airport, which is 45 km away.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Which are the nearest railway stations to NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "The nearest railway stations to NMAMIT are Udupi (40 km) and Mangaluru (50 km).\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Which highways are closest to NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "The highways closest to NMAMIT are the ones connecting Karkala and Padubidri, as Nitte is situated between these two towns.\nFor more information, visit https://www.google.co.in/maps/place/N.M.A.M.+Institute+of+Technology/@13.1830012,74.9316861,17.25z/data=!3m1!5s0x3bbcaa27e8fd79af:0x343962e5369a908a!4m6!3m5!1s0x3bbb56415ad85e5b:0x10b77ac6f6afc7fa!8m2!3d13.1830026!4d74.933989!16zL20vMDQxa25k?entry=ttu"
       },
       {
         "question": "What are the disciplines covered under the M.Tech. program in NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "The disciplines covered under the M.Tech. program include Construction Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Cyber Security, Electric Vehicle Technology, Machine Design, Structural Engineering, and VLSI Design & Embedded Systems.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "How many departments at NMAMIT offer research guidance for Ph.D. aspirants?",
         "answer": "All departments at NMAMIT offer research guidance for students interested in pursuing Ph.D.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "How many acres does NMAMIT's campus cover?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT's campus covers an area of 125 acres.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Are there any international collaborations for NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "Yes, NMAMIT has active collaborations with several international universities and organizations for faculty and student exchanges, research, internships, and placements.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What is the significance of NMAMIT's placement under the 'Platinum' category in AICTE-CII Survey?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT's placement under the 'Platinum' category indicates its high industry linkages, as recognized by the AICTE-CII Survey of Industry-Linked Technical Institutes 2020.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What is the significance of NBA accreditation for UG programs at NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "NBA accreditation signifies the quality and standards of the UG programs at NMAMIT, ensuring they meet the set benchmarks.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Are there any specific provisions for industry exposure at NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "Yes, NMAMIT has high industry linkages and collaborations, providing students with ample opportunities for industry exposure through internships, projects, and placements.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "How does NMAMIT promote research among its students?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT promotes research among its students by providing qualified research guides, facilities, and opportunities for collaborative projects.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What are the specialties of NMAMIT's PG programs?",
         "answer": "The specialties of NMAMIT's PG programs include various disciplines such as Construction Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Cyber Security, etc., catering to specific areas of expertise.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "How does NMAMIT ensure industry relevance in its curriculum?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT maintains industry relevance in its curriculum through collaborations, internships, projects, and regular updates to course content based on industry requirements.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT ensure industry relevance in its curriculum?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT maintains industry relevance in its curriculum through collaborations, internships, projects, and regular updates to course content based on industry requirements.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "Are there any provisions for co-curricular activities at NMAMIT?",
        "answer": "Yes, NMAMIT encourages co-curricular activities through clubs, societies, and events, fostering holistic development among students.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What measures does NMAMIT take to ensure quality education?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT ensures quality education through experienced faculty, modern infrastructure, industry collaborations, and accreditation processes.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT support student entrepreneurship?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT supports student entrepreneurship through incubation centers, mentorship programs, and industry tie-ups to nurture innovative ideas and startups.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What distinguishes NMAMIT from other engineering colleges?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT stands out due to its industry linkages, research opportunities, vibrant campus, and emphasis on holistic development.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the role of NMAMIT's faculty in fostering student growth?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT's faculty play a crucial role in mentoring, guiding, and inspiring students to excel academically and professionally.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT ensure student welfare on campus?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT ensures student welfare through counseling services, student support centers, and a conducive learning environment.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT contribute to regional development?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT contributes to regional development by providing skilled manpower, conducting research, and collaborating with local industries and communities.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What facilities does NMAMIT provide for sports and recreation?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT provides sports facilities, recreational spaces, and organizes events to promote physical fitness and extracurricular activities among students.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT promote innovation among its students?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT promotes innovation through hackathons, innovation labs, project competitions, and mentorship programs to nurture creativity and problem-solving skills.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What role does NMAMIT play in sustainable development?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT promotes sustainable practices through initiatives such as green campus initiatives, waste management programs, and awareness campaigns.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT ensure gender diversity on campus?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT encourages gender diversity through awareness programs, scholarships, and inclusive policies to create a supportive environment for all students.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What support does NMAMIT provide for career development?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT offers career counseling, skill development programs, placement assistance, and industry interactions to enhance students' employability.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT engage with the local community?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT engages with the local community through outreach programs, social initiatives, and collaborative projects to address societal needs and contribute to development.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What initiatives does NMAMIT take for student leadership development?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT offers leadership training, student council activities, and opportunities for participation in clubs and organizations to foster leadership skills among students.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT ensure academic excellence?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT ensures academic excellence through rigorous curriculum, continuous assessment, faculty development programs, and academic support services.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What are NMAMIT's future plans for growth and development?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT's future plans include expanding infrastructure, enhancing research facilities, strengthening industry collaborations, and promoting innovation and entrepreneurship among students.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is NMAM Institute of Technology's vision?",
        "answer": "NMAM Institute of Technology aims to pursue excellence, empower people, and partner in community development.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/vision-mission.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the mission of NMAM Institute of Technology?",
        "answer": "The mission of NMAM Institute of Technology is to develop as a Center of Excellence by imparting quality education to generate competent, skilled, and humane manpower capable of facing emerging scientific, technological, managerial, and social challenges with credibility, integrity, ethics, and social concern.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/vision-mission.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What are the core values upheld by NMAM Institute of Technology?",
        "answer": "NMAM Institute of Technology values ethics, teamwork, honesty, loyalty, and both professional and personal integrity.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/vision-mission.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is NMAM Institute of Technology's quality policy?",
        "answer": "NMAM Institute of Technology recognizes its students, their parents, and prospective employers as esteemed customers. The institute is committed to providing education as per stipulated syllabus using the best practices to achieve customer delight. Its target is to become one of the best technical institutes in India and sustain this position.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/vision-mission.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "who is the founder of nitte?",
        "answer": "LATE JUSTICE K. S HEGDE\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/founder.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "who is the Principal of NMAMIT?",
        "answer": "Prof. Niranjan N Chiplunkar\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/principal.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "who is the Vice principal & Dean of NMAMIT?",
        "answer": "Dr. I. Ramesh Mithanthaya\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/vice-principal.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "who is the Vice Principal & Controller of Examinations of NMAMIT?",
        "answer": "Dr. Shrinivasa Rao B.R.\nFor more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/vice-principal.php"
      }
   ]
}
